Preliminary Inventory of the Gale Lackey Papers, 1980s - 2014
Gale Lackey Papers1980s - 2014
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Gale Lackey
2015-11
2
Gale Lackey was a member of Wesleyan University's senior athletics department from 1978 to 2015. She served as the senior woman administrator in athletics and an associate athletics director, as well as an adjunct professor of physical education and an affiliated professor in women's studies (now FGSS). She coached the women's lacrosse and field hockey teams from 1978 to 1985, at which point she took over as the coach of women's volleyball. Lackey has the distinction of coaching Wesleyan women's teams to Little Three championships in three different sports (volleyball, field hockey and lacrosse). In 2001, she was named New England Small College Athletic Conference (NESCAC) Coach of the Year.
The Gale Lackey Papers include materials related to Wesleyan women's athletics teams, particularly the volleyball team. Materials are predominantly audiovisual and photographic, supplemented with personal notes, pamphlets, manuals and photocopies of published articles. The collection is unprocessed.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Gift of Gale Lackey, 2015.
Biographical Note
Gale Lackey was a member of Wesleyan University's senior athletics department from 1978 to 2015. She served as the senior woman administrator in athletics and an associate athletics director, as well as an adjunct professor of physical education and an affiliated professor in women's studies (now FGSS). She coached the women's lacrosse and field hockey teams from 1978 to 1985, at which point she took over as the coach of women's volleyball. Lackey has the distinction of coaching Wesleyan women's teams to Little Three championships in three different sports (volleyball, field hockey and lacrosse). In 2001, she was named New England Small College Athletic Conference (NESCAC) Coach of the Year. A 1970 graduate of West Chester St. College (now West Chester University), where she earned both her B.A. and M. Ed. degrees, Lackey spent seven years teaching and coaching field hockey and volleyball at Spring Grove (Pa.) High School before coaching a year of volleyball at the University of Bridgeport in 1977-78.
Collection Overview
The Gale Lackey Papers include materials related to Wesleyan women's athletics teams, particularly the volleyball team. Materials are predominantly audiovisual and photographic, supplemented with personal notes, pamphlets, manuals and photocopies of published articles. The collection is unprocessed.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Box 1: Wesleyan Women's Volleyball videocassette tapes
  - The Wesleyan Freeman Asian Scholars Program, videocassette (Box 1)
  - Channel 3 Feature Wesleyan Volleyball, videocassette,1989 (Box 1)
  - Wendy Hilliard Wesleyan University 25th-Year Celebration of Women in Sports, videocassette,1996 Apr 20 (Box 1)
  - Game 1 Wesleyan v. Amherst, videocassette (Box 1)
  - Game 2 Wesleyan v. Williams, videocassette (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Mt. Holyoke, videocassette (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. ECSU, videocassette,1993 Oct 26 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Mt. Holyoke senior night, videocassette,1998 Oct 29 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. ECSU at Wesleyan, videocassette,1999 Sept 28 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan v. Trinity, videocassette,1999 Oct (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan v. Smith invitational, videocassette,1999 Oct (Box 1)
  - Game 2 Wesleyan v. Smith, videocassette,2000 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan v. Trinity round 1 Wesleyan tournament, videocassette,2000 (Box 1)
  - ECSU Volleyball, videocassette,2001 Sept 25 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity, videocassette,2001 Sept 28 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Smith videocassette,2001 Sept 29 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Connecticut College, videocassette,2001 Oct 1 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Williams, videocassette,2001 Oct 5 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Hamilton, videocassette,2001 Oct 6 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. WCSU, videocassette,2001 Oct 17 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. WCSU at Wesleyan NCAA Regionals, videocassette,2001 Nov 8 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity, videocassette,2002 Oct 5 (Box 1)
  - Bates at Trinity, videocassette,2002 Oct 12 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bates at Williams NESCACs, videocassette,2002 Nov 8 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. WCSU home, videocassette,2003 Oct (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Amherst Wesleyan invitational, videocassette,2004 Oct 1 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity, videocassette,2004 Oct 16 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Williams, videocassette,2004 Nov 5 (Box 1)
- Box 2: CDs, photographs and related papers on Wesleyan Women's sports teams
  - Wesleyan v. Connecticut College, CD,---- Sept 19 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Connecticut College at Connecticut College, CD,---- Oct 30 (Box 2)
  - Title IX Feature WesU FM "Radio Active Wire", cassette tape,1997 Mar 2 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Amherst, CD,2005 Sept 30 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bates, CD,2005 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Amherst at Amherst, CD,2006 Sept 10 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Amherst at Amherst, CD (duplicate),2006 Sept 10 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Tufts, CD,2006 Sept 15 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bowdoin, CD,2006 Oct 27 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bowdoin, CD (duplicate),2006 Oct 27 (Box 2)
  - Wellesley Won 3-1, CD,2007 Sept 8 (Box 2)
  - Wiliams at Wellesley, CD,2007 Sept 8 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity, CD,2007 Sept 29 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Amherst games 1-4, CD,2007 Sept 29 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Amherst games 4-5, CD,2007 Sept 29 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity NESCAC, CD,2007 Oct 5 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Amherst, CD,2007 Oct 12 (Box 2)
  - ECSU senior night, CD,2007 Oct 17 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Williams, CD,2008 Sept 5 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Trinity, CD,2008 Oct 4 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Connecticut College, CD,2008 Oct 5 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bowdoin, CD,2008 Oct 17 (Box 2)
  - Springfield Volleyball, CD,2009 Sept 25 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut College at MIT, CD,2009 Sept 26 (Box 2)
  - Vassar at MIT, CD,2009 Sept 26 (Box 2)
  - Williams at MIT, CD,2009 Sept 26 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bates, CD,2009 Oct 3 (Box 2)
  - Williams at Connecticut College Won 3-2, CD,2009 Oct 9 (Box 2)
  - Middlebury at Connecticut College, CD,2009 Oct 10 (Box 2)
  - Amherst Lost 2-3, CD,2009 Oct 17 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Tufts NESCACs, CD,2009 Nov 6 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Tufts NESCACs at Tufts, CD (duplicate),2009 Nov 6 (Box 2)
  - Keene St, CD,2010 Sept 15 (Box 2)
  - Williams Volleyball, CD,2010 Sept 18 (Box 2)
  - Hamilton Volleyball, CD,2010 Sept 18 (Box 2)
  - Wentworth, CD,2010 Sept 25 (Box 2)
  - West Connecticut, CD,2010 Sept 29 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Bowdoin, CD,2010 Oct 1 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Volleyball, CD,2010 Oct 2 (Box 2)
  - Trinity, CD,2010 Oct 8 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Volleyball, CD,2010 Oct 9 (Box 2)
  - Amherst Quarter Finals, CD,2010 Nov 5 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Williams, CD,2011 Sept 30 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Hamilton, CD,2011 Oct 1 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Middlebury, CD,2012 Sept 14 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. WSU, CD,2012 Sept 14 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Williams, CD,2012 Sept 15 (Box 2)
  - Eastern Connecticut, CD,2012 Sept 18 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Tufts, CD,2012 Sept 29 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball v. Bates 3-0, CD,2012 Oct 13 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. RIC, CD,2012 Oct 16 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. ECSU, CD,2013 Sept 13 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Clark, CD,2013 Sept 14 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. Connecticut College, CD,2013 Sept 20 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan v. RWY, CD,2013 Sept 21 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball team photo, framed,2012 (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball team photo, framed,circa 1980s (Box 2)
  - Color photographs Wesleyan Women's Volleyball, envelope,2005-2014 (Box 2)
  - BW and color photographs Wesleyan Women's sports, envelope,1979-1989 (Box 2)
  - BW and color photographs Wesleyan Women's sports, envelope,1992-2014 (Box 2)
  - NESCAC Sports Illustrated article (Pure and Simple), folder (Box 2)
  - Wesleyan Volleyball manual,2011 (Box 2)
  - History of Wesleyan Women's Sports, folder (Box 2)
  - Volleyball newsletter, folder (Box 2)